Guide to the Sterling Beckwith Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Sterling Beckwith papers
1929-1992
SC0553
Beckwith, Sterling
45 Linear feet
Papers pertain to his interest and work in engineering and include drawings, notes, publications, correspondence, reports, plans, financial records, manuals, photographs, and patent files. Subjects include helicopters and polycopters, hydroelectric projects (including that of Paradise, California), the Nitrafix Process [recovery of nitrogen from engine exhaust], turbine generators, vehicles and transportation, and Chicago Stock Yards Research Division files. The collection also includes two films ("Tow Test Films" and "Polycopter Indoors & Outdoors").
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Engineer and inventor, Sterling Beckwith earned his A.B. at Stanford University in 1927 and his M.S. at Pittsburgh in 1929.
Description of the Collection
Papers pertain to his interest and work in engineering and include drawings, notes, publications, correspondence, reports, plans, financial records, manuals, photographs, and patent files. Subjects include helicopters and polycopters, hydroelectric projects (including that of Paradise, California), the Nitrafix Process [recovery of nitrogen from engine exhaust], turbine generators, vehicles and transportation, and Chicago Stock Yards Research Division files. The collection also includes two films ("Tow Test Films" and "Polycopter Indoors & Outdoors").
Access Terms
Beckwith, Sterling; Engineering.; Helicopters; Hydroelectric power plants.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Articles, Memos (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Stock Market publications 1972-1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Pump Sales Brochures and Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Stock Market Charts & Graphs (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Electric Power Research Institute (EPRI) Turbine report 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - MVS vs. Repumping (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pressurized Rotor (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pressurized Stator (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Garrett Blade Cooling (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - EPRI Pressurized Cooling (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Supercharged Generator 1955 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Co. (A-C) 2-401/4-240 428 NW (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - A-C 1958 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - A-C Electromagnetic Pump report (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - A-C Vacuum Brake patent (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - A-C Refrigeration for Generator Cooling Water (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - A-C K Factor report (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - A-C Magnetic (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - A-C Pressurized Generator Cooling (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Pressurized Cooling 1975 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - External Supercharge Boosting (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Magnetohydrodynamic (MHD) Power Generator Patent (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Westinghouse Pressurized Cooling (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Bendikson, Don (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Professional Engineer Memberships (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Professional Engineer Memberships (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - B. Offen & Co. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - A-C Disposal Unit (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Prince Armour- Donovan (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Project Tenderloin – Isbrandtsen, Morrison (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Chicago Stockyards Patent/ TM binder (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Metals for Low Temperature Use (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Nitrafix Nitrogen Fixation (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Nitrafix 1956 Experimental Data (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Nitrafix Smith, Don (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Nitrafix Mueller, Walter memos 1956 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Nitrafix Weir Box Calculation (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Nitrafix Evans – Hydraulic Labyrinth Converter (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Nitrafix Binder (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Nitrafix P.D. 7 General (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Nitrafix P.D. 7 Notes on Water Tests/ Watering Periods (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Nitrafix P.D. 7 Data Sheets (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Nitrafix P.D. 7 Anderson- Clayton (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Nitrafix P.D. 7 Soil-Water Data, Map (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Nitrafix Waukesha Engine Tests (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Nitrafix Estimated Expenditures (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Nitrafix Economics (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Nitrafix Texas A&M/Arizona (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Nitrafix Inquiries 1957 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Nitrafix Anderson-Clayton (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Nitrafix Waukesha Motor Co (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Nitrafix Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Nitrafix Royalty (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Nitrafix J.D. Kelley memos (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Nitrafix (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Nitrafix pH & Nitrogen Determinations (Texas & Arizona) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Nitrafix Nitrogen Fixation (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Nitrafix Nitronic Corp (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Nitrafix Results from Pecos Cotton Test Plots 1957 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Nitrafix Report & Notes (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Nitrafix Binder- Background (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Dept. of Water & Power (City of Los Angeles) Castaic Power Project: Preliminary (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - DWP Syn Start (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - DWP Tehachapi Pumping Plant R&D Program (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - DWP Castaic Coil Failure & Tests (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - DWP Photographs (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - DWP Castaic Pump Specs Report (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - DWP Rim Stress (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - DWP ASEA Stresses (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - DWP WR2 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - DWP Castaic Fans 1971 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - DWP Castaic & ASEA (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - DWP (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - DWP (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - DWP Castaic 70 MVA Unit (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - DWP Bolt Failure Report (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - DWP Seneca (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Photographs & Negatives (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - 16mm Films ("Tow Test Films" and "Polycopter Indoors & Outdoors"), Slides (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Negatives (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Box of Metal Parts (prototypes?) (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Negatives & Extra Photographs Engineering File 3.14.1 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Photographs – Fire Exposure (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Perspective 02-07-021 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Methane Photographs 4271, 4573, 4577 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Methane Photographs 5324, 5325, 5327, 5363, 5364, 5365, 5369, 5370, 5786 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Methane Photographs 5004, 5006, 5007, 5011, 5012 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Methane Photographs 3811, 3842 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Methane Photographs 4093, 4122, 4125, 4258, 4259 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Methane Photographs Gluing & Machining (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Methane Photographs Views Tank #3 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Methane Photographs Lining (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Methane Photographs Gluing Top & Bottom Panel (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Methane Photographs Pre-Lining (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Methane Photographs 3255 Barge Methane Quarter Bow View (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Methane Photographs Positioning Pressure Blanket (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Methane Photographs 4570 Applying Glue to Balsa Panel (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Methane Photographs 4572 Positioning Bottom Edge Pressure Blanket (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Methane Photographs 4574 Putting Balsa Panel in Place (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Methane Photographs 4575 Positioning End Pressure Pad (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Methane Photographs 4576 Units in Place (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Methane Photographs 4578 Positioning Top Pressure Pad (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Methane Photographs 8984 Barge Methane Lining Construction (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Methane Pascagoula Liquid Air Tests (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Methane Test Report on Cargo Barge Methane: IV Disposal (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Methane Balsa Box Photographs & Negatives (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Methane Record of Cold Spots 5/14/1956 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Methane Bayou Long Test Data (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Turbochiller - Southwest Research Institute (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Nitrafix Test 16-03-xxx (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Nitrafix Economics (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Liquifreeze Method (LQF) (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Helicopter (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Chicago Stockyards Research Division- Compost (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Methane Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Soap Formula (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Soap Machine & Patents (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Upgrading of Fats (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Fats (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Methane Reports (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Nitrafix Scientific Literature (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Equilibrium Composition Report (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Nitrafix Field Notebook Phoenix 1958 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Methane Report Eng. File 3.15.7 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Methane Report Eng. File 3.15.4 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Nitrometer: A Photoelectric Colorimeter (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Turbochiller Report (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Turbochiller Patent (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Methane Reports (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - LQF Report Eng. File 5.5.6 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Nitrafix Report (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Rectangular Tank for Testing Surface Woods (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Methane Centrifugal Unloading Pump #1 Tank Test (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Methane Test of Vents & Flares (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Methane Fire Ignition Distance, Radiant Heat Distance (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Methane Report 5/1957 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Drawings, Photographs, Metal Parts, Notes (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Sunbeam Corp. 1973 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Quotation Requests (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Paul E. Gerst & Co. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Electrical Products, Cleveland (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Howard Industries, Inc. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Winpower correspondence, motes (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Winpower 500w MIL General Description (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Winpower 500w MIL Correspondence (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Winpower 153 General (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Winpower 15kw Military Tests 11/1962 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Winpower 15kw (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Winpower 1500w MIL (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Winpower 1500w 7' Frame 4" Diameter (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Winpower C7 Current Transformer (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Winpower (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Winpower 500w MIL Revolving Arm (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Winpower 2500w 10" Frame, 6" Diameter (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Winpower 5kw 1800rpm (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Winpower 5kw 3600rpm (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Winpower 500w 60 Cycle 3600rpm Alternator (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Winpower Miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - SKIL Corp. (Gerst) (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Dental Motor (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Dahlco Electric Co., Inc. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Pesco Products Division, Borg-Warner Co. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Lundahl (Moon Manufacturing Co.) Old Quotes (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Winpower 2500 & 3000w 60 Cycle 3600rpm Alternators (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Gilman & Snyder (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Winpower 3kw Prototype - Gil - Index V (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Winpower 75kva (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Winpower Engineering Specs 1-28 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Winpower Miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Winpower 3500w 3600 rpm 120v 60 Cycle Regulator (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Winpower PEG Mg Set (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Winpower PEG Co. 1000w PM Generator 115v 60 Cycle (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Winpower 30v 300a 9kw 3500+rpm Military Development (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Winpower 500kw Mic Nipper (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Winpower 300w 3600rpm Ballard (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Winpower Pittsburgh Plate Glass Co. (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Winpower 1500w to 4000w 2 Pole (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Winpower 12kva Sparrow (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - AIEE Technical Papers (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Curtiss-Wright Corp. - Acoustics (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Ball Mills 1/13/1948 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Balance 24000rpm (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - C-W Balance (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Engineering Report 5.3.1 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Bearing Tests- Turbo Generator (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Bearing Data, F&W (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Journal Bearing Vibration Test 2.10.1 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Journal Bearing Oil Film & HP Test Results (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Ball Bearings (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Ball Bearings MRC Bulletins (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Brazing (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Bi-Metal (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Compressed Air Heating (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Cooler Tests (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Coolers (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Coolers – Axial Fin Tests (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Copper (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Core Loss Turbo Generator 2.16.8 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Load Loss (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Core Loss in Salient Pole Machine (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - U.S. Steel Electrical Steel Sheets Manual (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Critical Speeds – Stresses at 29-331/4 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Critical Speeds Balancing of Asymmetrical Shafts (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Critical Speeds (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Experiments - Old (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Editorial Board (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Electro-motive (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Fans - Ventilation Fan (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Fans (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Fans (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Fans - Ventilation of Revolving Field Salient Pole Alternators (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Fans – Screw Propeller Experiments- Schmidt (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Fans – Propeller-type Fan - Tietjens (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Fans Articles (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Fans – Propeller Fan Articles (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Fans – Application of Propeller Fans to Electric Machinery (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Fans- Contraction Coefficents (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Fans – Design of Propeller Fans (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Forging (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Heating on Synchronous Machine - Rotor (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Heating on Synchronous Machine – Stator 2-24-A (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Heat Transfer (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Induction Motor- Levine's Article Data 1/3 HP (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Induction Motor Small 3 HP Wound Rotor (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - K vs. Temperature (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Insulation Test (Steel Plate) (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Kingsbury Machine Works (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Laboratory (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Lightning Protection (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Methane 588-589 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Microfilm (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Neutral Grounding for Steel Mills (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Magnetic Noise (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Noise #2 Baffle Tests (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Noise #3 Meter Calibration (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Noise (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Originals & Negatives, Standard Design Data (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Thermistors (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Bay Area Rapid Transit vs. Southern Pacific (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Bay Area Rapid Transit vs. Southern Pacific (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Composting (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - DWP Castaic Bearing (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - DWP 360,000 HP (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Chainsaws (McCulloch) (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Helicopter - McCulloch Motors (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Helicopter (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Helicopter 1960 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Helicopter /Hovercraft Clippings, Brochures, Reports, Correspondence (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Helicopter Navy (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Helicopter (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Helicopter Summary (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Helicopter - Terracopter (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Helicopter - Terracopter Log (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Helicopter - Terracopter (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Helicopter 22 Starter (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Helicopter 22 Starter (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Helicopter - Others (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Helicopter - Others – Photographs (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Helicopter Designs (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Helicopter Correspondence (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Helicopter Notes, Correspondence, Reports, Photographs (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Helicopter Collective Pitch Devices (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Helicopter -2 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Helicopter Model 22 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Helicopter (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Helicopter Flight Manual Drafts (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Helicopter Articles, Drawings (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Helicopter Patents (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Helicopter Navy Hydroplane ASW (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Helicopter XHP (ASW) (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Helicopter Invoices, Purchase Orders, Correspondence (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Helicopter Model 21B Drawings, & Layouts, Old (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Helicopter Dusting (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Helicopter Calculations- Cone (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Helicopter 30 Invoices, Purchase Orders, Correspondence (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Helicopter Quotes (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Helicopter Correspondence (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Helicopter NACA (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Helicopter Lab & Test Equipment (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Helicopter Model 20 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Helicopter Model 21 Gears (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Helicopter Publicity (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Helicopter Receiving Records (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Helicopter Civil Aeronautics (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Helicopter Model 21A Layouts, Old (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Methane Miscellaneous (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Reports- Properties of Metals (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Cockpit Cooling Material (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - American Institute of Electrical Engineers (AIEE) Talk, 10/16/1952 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Thesis Advisor (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Thesis Advisors (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Vortex Tube (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Fisk Failure (Spindle) (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Rosenberg, L.T. (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Alger, Philip L. (Lamme Candidate) (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Small Refrigerator (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Remote Control Mower (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Beckwith - Lamme Award (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - A-C Design Catalogs (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Saturation Curves (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Turbogenerator Rotors- Mechanical Design Data (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Design Data (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Westinghouse Reprints (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Syn Cond. 51 3/8 Diameter or Less (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Standard Cond. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Salient Pole Designs, Under 100" (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Turbogenerator- Future Changes (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Standardized 20 & 30,000 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Staats, G.W. Thesis (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Beckwith Personal Correspondence (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Time Delay Switch (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - PF Bridge (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - CalteenThesis (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Small Motors (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Flex Shaft (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Stock Market (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Helicopter (3) Logbooks & Correspondence (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Helicopter Articles etc. (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Helicopter (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Helicopter GV Geared Starter (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Helicopter First Polycopter (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Helicopter 3kw Prototype, No Core (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Helicopter Starter & Magneto (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Helicopter Model 22 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Helicopter NX 3411 (Operating) (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Helicopter Agreements (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Helicopter Model 21B Drawings, Tracings (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Helicopter Lycoming Correspondence (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Helicopter Model 21A Drawings (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Helicopter Model 21B Drawings (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Helicopter Model 21B Drawings (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Helicopter Drawings, 5 & 700-000 Series (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Helicopter Drawings, 2-3 & 400-000 Series (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Helicopter Drawings, 100-000 Series (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Helicopter Motor & Generator (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Helicopter Extra Prints, Dev. Auth. 7361 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Helicopter Unsorted 1944-1948 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Helicopter Model 20 & 21 Calculations, Old (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Helicopter Model 21-B Stress (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Helicopter Drop Tests (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Helicopter Miscellaneous Tests (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Helicopter Miscellaneous 1943-1944 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Beckwith Personal Correspondence (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Helicopter Model 21 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Helicopter Articles (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Helicopter Miscellaneous 1940's (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Helicopter Drawings, Old (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Helicopter Airfoils (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Helicopter Auth. 7361 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Helicopter Civil Aeronautics Administration (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Beckwith Personal Correspondence (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Helicopter Articles (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Helicopter NX 34111 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Reports, Magazines, Other Publications (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Gazis, Denos C. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Reports, Magazines, Other Publications (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - AIEE Reports (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Consulting- Inactive Accounts - Sunbeam (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Consulting- Inactive Accounts - Curtiss-Wright, Utica (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Consulting- Inactive Accounts - A.O. Smith (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Consulting- Inactive Accounts - Dowell (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Consulting- Inactive Accounts - Isbrandtsen-WLM (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Consulting- Inactive Accounts - Clark Brothers 1958-1959 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Consulting- Inactive Accounts - Clark Brothers (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Beckwith Articles, Reports, Papers, Correspondence (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Tehachapi Reports (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Winpower Miscellaneous (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Airesearch (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Armour & Co. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Armour Report (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Armour Advanced Concepts Research (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Armour Cycle Analysis (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Bangor Punta (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Bangor Punta (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Bangor Punta Snowmobile (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Bangor Punta Snowmobile (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Bangor Punta Bartlett – Snow- Pacific (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Bangor Punta Cushion Flight Information Packet (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Burns & Roe, Inc. (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Caterpillar (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Caterpillar (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Caterpillar Deposition (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Century Electric Co. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Century Variable Speed Generator (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Garrett Airesearch Report (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Garrett CP (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Garrett Inductance (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Garrett (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Garrett (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Garrett (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - SRI Linear Accelerator (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Alexander Kusko, Inc. (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Arthur D. Little, Inc. (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Armed Services (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - C.I. G.R.E. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - AIEE Education Committee (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - American Standards Association 10/8 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - AIEE Standards Committee (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - ASA 45-C-42 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - ASA 45-C-42 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - AIEE Standards Committee (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - ASA C-73 Attachment Plugs (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - AIEE Standards Coordinating Committee #4 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - AIEE Standards Committee Rotating Machine 52-3 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - AIEE Standards Committee (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Louis Allis Co. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Louis Allis Co. (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Marathon Electric Manufacturing Corp. – Specs & Correspondence (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Marathon 2-10-9 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Marathon New Drawings (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Marathon (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Marathon 100kw AC Generator with Brushless Exciter Drawings (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Marathon 2 Pole Miscellaneous (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Marathon Drawings- Reference (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Marathon Revised New Design (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Marathon 2-81/4-11/4 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Marathon 2 Pole Order (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Marathon Paper Mill Drive (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Marathon Photographs (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Marathon Pipe Line Motors (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Marathon Sparking Reports (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Mather Co. (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Manitoba Hydro (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Northfield Generator Drawings (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Winpower 400~500w MIL (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Winpower 28v dc 500w MIL (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Continental Motors Corp. R&D Report 1959 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Winpower 60~500w MIL (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Southern Illinois Stone Co. (Box 34, Folder 9)